《无垠的太空》前情提要
Previously on The Expanse...
他缺氧了
He's hypoxic.
他的呼吸器不行了
His breather's crapping out!
你可以吸我的氧
You can breathe off mine, okay?
深呼吸
Breathe it in.
我叫詹姆斯·霍顿
My name is James Holden,
信息已收取
发送坐标
代表坎特伯雷号的五名幸存者
speaking for the five survivors of the Canterbury.
我们的飞船回应了来自海岩号的
Our ship was destroyed answering
假求救信号后被毁
a bogus sos from a ship called the Scopuli.
我们马上要被带进火星舰队的唐纳吉尔号
We are about to be taken aboard the MCRN Donnager.
-亚历克斯 把他关了 -我们有权请
- Alex, shut him down! - We have the right to legal...
天啊 毛小姐 你可真会挑人
Good golly, Ms. Mao. You sure can pick 'em.
麦迪纳现在实行宵禁
Curfew is now in effect on Medina level.
你觉得我是外行星联盟的吗
Do you think I'm OPA?
这些都是恐怖分子的特有技能
These are the hallmark skill sets of terrorists.
不是火星摧毁的坎特伯雷号
Mars didn't destroy the Canterbury.
那是谁干的
Then who did?
在我加入坎特号之前
I flew with the Mars Navy for 20 years
我在火星舰队飞了二十多年
before I shipped off on the Cant.
你是外行星联盟的人吗
Are you OPA?
我们把事情都摊开来说吧
We putting all our cards on the table here?
-潜伏特工 你们听说过没有 -去死吧
- Sleeper agents. You ever heard of them? - Well, screw you...
-伙计 -人盾 你听过吗
- Guys! - Human shields, you ever heard of those?
我准备好谈话了 但是只和你们舰长谈
Hey! I'm ready to talk, but only to your Captain.
各位 已经结束了 回家去吧
Come on, guys, it's over. Just... Just go home.
还没结束 地球人 这才刚开始
It's not over, Earther. It's just beginning
不不不
No, no, no!
谷神星_空间站
位于小行星带
抱歉让你久等 我们今天有点忙
Sorry to keep you waiting, we've been busier than usual.
还不断从麦迪纳送过来 连上城的都有
Still getting intakes from all over the Medina, even from uptown.
你知道地球的人均预期寿命是多少吗
You know what the average life expectancy on Earth is?
不知道
No.
123岁 火星上还要更长
123 years. It's even better on Mars.
你知道谷神星上是多少吗 68岁
You know what it is on Ceres? 68.
加上最近这些不幸的事
And with the recent unpleasantness,
这个数字只会更低
that average is only going down.
怎么了
What?
没什么 我肯定你比看起来年轻
Nothing. I'm sure you're younger than you look.
尸检中
扫描受损情况
死者身份是比齐·贝迪克
Stiff's ID is Bizi Betiko.
贝迪克
比齐
谷神星
12区42层
男性
他的文件里没有写宗教丧葬要求
You know, there is no religious directive on file,
所以我可以把他送去资源回收吗
so okay if I recycle him?
39层的工厂需要一些肥料
Factory on 39 needs some fertilizer.
先不要
Not yet.
火星舰队_唐纳吉尔号
木星附近
我想知道霍顿
I'd like to know what the hell
到底在和舰长讨论什么
Holden is discussing with the Captain right now.
他完全有可能是在谈交易
For all we know, he could be working out a deal.
是啊 为他自己的交易
Yeah, for himself.
我只看到一艘船朝这里驶来
The only thing I see here is an incoming ship.
你们都查不出是什么船
One you can't even identify.
又怎么知道他们是为了奈奥米来的
How do you know they're coming for Naomi?
我们不知道 只是个猜测
We don't. It's a guess.
你们说奈奥米是外行星联盟的人也是猜测吧
And you're just guessing Naomi's OPA, too.
你我都知道那可不只是猜测
We both know that's better than a guess.
到目前为止 她是你们中最会说谎的人
She is the best liar amongst all of you, by far.
而且她隐瞒了什么 你也能感觉到
And she is hiding something. You can sense that, too.
我不相信她是恐怖分子
I don't believe she's a terrorist.
就算她是 我也不相信坎特伯雷号是她炸的
And even if she was, I'm not blaming her for the Canterbury.
你说是我们炸的
You blamed it on us.
我们在诱我们去海岩号的信号源里
We found Martian Naval tech
发现了火星舰队的技术
in the beacon that lured us to the Scopuli,
然后你们就出现了
and then you showed up.
我们跟坎特伯雷号的事毫无关系
We had nothing to do with the Canterbury,
但就因为你 地球认为是我们炸毁了它
but because of you, Earth thinks we destroyed it.
有些人在说这是战争行为
Some people are calling it an act of war.
你得宣布撤回声明
You need to recant.
说是永田干的 不管是不是真的
Blame Nagata. True or not,
这都能改变情况 直到人们冷静下来
it will change the narrative until cooler heads prevail
查出究竟是怎么回事
and figure out what really happened.
我不会那样做的
I won't do it.
有人在玩什么把戏
There's some kind of game being played here.
或许有人想要引发一场战争 我不知道
Maybe someone wants a war, I don't know,
但如果你们真的想要阻止战争发生
but if you really do want to stop it,
那就放了我们 然后我们再谈
then let us go and then we talk.
舰长 驶近船只
Captain, inbound vessel
正在进入防御范围 一分钟后接触界线
approaching defense perimeter. One minute to contact.
-呼叫他们 -呼叫频道打开
- Hail them. - Frequencies open.
不明身份船只
Unidentified vessel,
我是火星舰队唐纳吉尔号舰长特雷莎·姚
this is Captain Theresa Yao, of the MCRN Donnager.
这是对你们的最后一次警告
This is your final warning.
如果你们继续前进 我们就要开火了
If you maintain your present course you will be fired upon.
他们干扰了我们的通讯
They're jamming us.
检测到多个快速移动物体
Multiple fast movers detected!
不只一艘船 我数有六艘敌舰
More than one ship. I count six bandits.
导弹发射警报
Missile launch alert.
拉响全舰警报 全体人员进入战斗岗位
Sound general quarters. All hands, battle stations.
准备还击
Prepare to return fire.
发生什么事了
What's happening?
这是战斗模式照明 一定是演习
That's battle mode lighting. Must be a drill.
好吧 那是什么
Okay, what's that?
听起来像是在发射鱼雷
It sounds like torpedoes being fired.
听起来发射了很多鱼雷
Sounds like a lot of torpedoes.
我觉得这不是演习
I don't think it's a drill.
或许我们应该系上安全带
Maybe we should get strapped in.
好主意
Good idea.
鱼雷已发射 导航系统锁定所有目标
Torpedoes are away! Guidance lock on all targets.
不管他们是谁 不管他们是来干什么的
Well, whoever they are, and whatever they've come to do,
这都刚刚变成了一项自杀任务
it's just become a suicide mission.
是他们挑起战斗的 而我们会结束这场战斗
They started this fight, and we're going to finish it.
无垠的太空
第一季 第四集
By aBu 20170428
地球_和_月球
联合国
我们不知道他们在和谁战斗
We can't tell who they're fighting.
有大量雷达干扰
There's massive ladar and radar jamming,
我们没法辨别引擎特征
we can't resolve the drive signatures
也没法通过外形辨别船的身份
or make any visual IDs.
他们抓了我们的人做人质
They took our people hostage.
我们必须派一艘船过去
We have to get a ship there.
奥利诺科号已经尽快往那里赶了
The Orinoco's en route at best possible speed,
但他们还有两天才能到
but they're still two days out.
到时候一切都结束了
It'll all be over by then.
有什么人拥有了一支新的战船舰队
Somebody has a new fleet of warships.
我同意 能猜到有可能是谁吗
I concur. Any idea who it might be?
还没想到 有消息随时通知我
Not yet. Keep me apprised.
我小时候 比人们以为的要聪明
While I was so young, I was wiser than they thought.
"亲爱的" 我说 "惩罚可是死亡"
"Dear, dear," says I, "punishment is death."
"是啊" 他说 "如果他们能抓到我"
"Aye," says he, "if they can get hands on me."
目标15分钟内到达
Incoming targets at 15...
我们加一个显示...
Let's get an additional readout on this...
你看起来有点紧张
You look nervous.
有导弹向我飞来的时候我就会这样
I get that way when missiles are flying at me.
别担心 我们的武器对付得了
Don't worry. It's nothing our guns can't handle.
我猜你在联合国舰队中没见过多少战斗对吗
I take it you didn't see much action in the UN Navy?
-那是好事 -对士兵来说不是
- That was a good thing. - Not for soldiers.
我的军官们大多只在模拟演习中见过战斗
The only combat most of my officers have seen is in simulators.
幸运的是 我有机会
Fortunately, I got to spend
在小行星带参与了三年剿灭海盗行动
three years cleansing the belt of pirates
扫荡那些抢劫火星星球改造物资的海盗
who were poaching terraforming supplies intended for Mars.
我肯定他们不全是坏人
I'm sure they weren't all bad people.
但有时候必须通过杀戮来保卫生存
But sometimes you have to kill to preserve.
姚舰长 请到2号通讯台
Captain Yao, you're needed on comms deck two.
定点防御炮准备好了吗
PDCs ready?
全阵列已经连线准备好了
All arrays are online and standing by.
外公说你不该到屋顶上来
Appa says you shouldn't be on the roof.
那你就应该吗
And you should?
你不用害怕它们的
They're nothing to be scared of, you know.
他们不过就是些小石头 在天空中燃烧
They're just little rocks that burn up in the sky.
他们并不是都这么小
They're not always so little.
你是说杀死恐龙的那颗吗
You mean like the one that killed the dinosaurs?
好吧 那块石头是很大
Okay, that rock was big.
但那种情况很罕见的
But that hardly ever happens.
比中彩票还难
Like winning the lottery.
我担心的是那些扔石头的人们
I worry about people who throw rocks.
没人能扔得动那么大的石头
Nobody could throw rocks that big.
那只是自然发生的事情 因为重力什么的
It just happens, sometimes, because, you know, gravity.
进来陪我们玩吧
Come in and play.
一会儿我进去送你们上床睡觉
I'll come and put you to bed.
你真没意思
You're no fun.
我能问个问题吗
May I ask you a question?
你想念地球吗
Do you miss Earth?
我要是想 就回去了
If I did, I'd go back.
我叔公是从地球移民到火星的
My great-uncle emigrated from Earth.
他特别想念那里
He missed it terribly.
我小时候他经常给我讲故事
He used to tell me stories when I was a little boy
那一望无际的蓝天
about these endless blue skies,
到处都可以自由呼吸
free air everywhere.
广袤的大海直连天际
Open water all the way to the horizon.
他告诉我有一天我们也会把火星建成那样
He told me that someday we would make Mars just like that.
对于一辈子生活在穹顶之下的人而言
When you spend your whole life living under a dome,
即使是海洋这样一个概念都难以想象
even the idea of an ocean seems impossible to imagine.
我永远理解不了你们这些人
I could never understand your people.
宇宙赐予你们如此丰厚的礼物
Why, when the universe had bestowed so much upon you,
你们为什么却似乎毫不关心
you seemed to care so little for it.
毁灭是地球人最擅长的事情
Wrecking things is what Earthers do best.
火星人也是 从你们战舰的样子看
Martians, too, by the look of your ship.
我们和你们完全不一样
We are nothing like you.
地球人关心的只是政府的施舍
The only things Earthers care about is government handouts.
免费食物 免费水 免费毒品
Free food, free water, free drugs
这样你们就可以忘却你们漫无目标的人生
so that you can forget the aimless lives you lead.
你们是一群短视自私的人
You're short-sighted and selfish,
而这会毁了你们
and it will destroy you.
进攻鱼雷进入定点防御炮火力范围 一分钟
Incoming torpedoes in PDC range, one minute.
地球已经完了 霍顿先生
Earth is over, Mr. Holden.
我只希望我们能赶在你们也把火星毁灭之前
My only hope is that we can bring Mars to life
让它焕发生机
before you destroy that, too.
看好犯人
Secure the prisoner.
遵命 长官
Yes, sir.
坐到椅子上去
Get in the chair.
系上
Come on.
希望你喜欢这场表演
I hope you enjoy the show.
锁定定点防御炮然后开火
Lock PDCs and engage.
定点防御炮开火
PDCs are go.
毁掉一艘 还剩五艘
Splash one! Five more to go.
有问题吗
Is there a problem?
没有 长官
No, sir,
只是他们的鱼雷导航系统真的很优秀
it's just their torps' guidance systems are really good.
比我们在模拟战斗里见过的都要好
Better than anything we ever simmed against.
让定点防御炮尽全力才能防御
They're pushing our PDCs to the limit.
主反应器舱被击中
Impact on main reactor housing.
舰长 敌舰进入制导导弹火力范围
Captain, enemy ships are now inside guided missile range.
鱼雷已经不再有效力了
Torpedoes will no longer be effective.
够了 启动轨道炮
Enough of this. Bring up the rail guns.
我们赶紧结束战斗回家去
Let's finish this and go home.
遵命 长官 将能量转移至轨道炮
Aye, sir. Diverting power to rail guns.
铭记坎特号
我要找比齐·贝迪克
I'm looking for Bizi Betiko.
你在这里可找不到他
You're not going to find him here.
为什么这么说
Why you pensa?
你为什么这么说
-为什么这么说 -你为什么这么说
- Why you pensa? - Why you pensa?
-这是他家 是吗 -对 是的
- This is his place, right? - So, ya, that it is.
这就意味着我已经驾驶普拉号
Which puts me at 29 days,
在无动力下飞行了
seven hours and 13 minutes of Pura,
29天7小时13分了
unpowered flight.
我会绕木星转向 然后高速...
I carve it up around the big-gas, then load up more spin...
-罗曼诺夫 -绕过土星环
- Romanov. - Going 'round the ringer.
还有三百万公里的绝对真空
It's only three million clicks of hard vacuum
我就要冲向比蚊子屁股还小的靶心了
to hit a bull's-eye smaller than a mosquito's ass
然后就可以让我永载飞行史册
and fly my way into the record books.
引力弹弓俱乐部
Slingshot club.
是的 只是娱乐大众 长官
Yeah. Oh, for entertainment purposes only, sasa ke.
不需要执照的
No license required.
我根本不关心什么狗屁执照
Ah, I don't give a crap about that. Huh?
那想要赌一把吗 今晚这一出很不错哦
Wanna bet, ke? Action good tonight.
好了 都听我说 我是恒星螺旋警察
All right, listen up! Star Helix.
我在找一个女孩
I'm looking for a girl.
她叫朱莉 曾经是个驾驶员
Her name's Julie, she was a pilot.
她可能来找比齐租过一艘船
She might've come to Bizi to charter a ship?
这边
Here.
混蛋们 比齐·贝迪克死了
Hey, assholes. Bizi Betiko is dead.
他还没死呢 笨警察 他在那里
He ain't dead yet, copeng. He be out there.
那就是比齐·贝迪克
That Bizi Betiko!
看好我是怎么成功的...
Watch the way it's done...
贝迪克
比齐
谷神星
12区42层
男性
胜利
Sabaka!
比齐 比齐 比齐 比齐
Bizi, Bizi, Bizi, Bizi!
加油 加油
Come on, come on, come on.
加油啊 加油啊
加油 加油
Come on, come on, come on.
现在他死了
Now he dead.
你应该赌的 你真该赌一把的
Should've bet. Should've bet.
第谷_空间站
位于小行星带
诺伍号的引擎都已经通过了检测和认证
The Nauvoo's engines have all been tested and certified,
我们同时
and we've been able to
还在继续完成船体外壳的建造
continue laying down the hull at the same time.
也就是说 一切都在按计划进行
Which means, everything is proceeding on schedule
也在预算之内 我相信你听到一定会很高兴
and on budget, which I'm sure you're pleased to hear.
约翰逊先生
Mr. Johnson.
后期圣徒教会雇你来建造诺伍号
The Latter Day Saints took a considerable risk
是冒了一定风险的
hiring you to build the Nauvoo.
我知道
I know.
第谷公司主营加速行星自转
Tycho spins up asteroids.
我们并没有造船业务 以前没有过
We don't build ships, not till now.
但相信我 这会成为一艘令世人难忘的船
But trust me, it'll be a ship no one will ever forget.
我不是这个意思
That's not what I meant.
我是指你 有些人在讨论
I meant you. There have been rumblings
应该把这个项目的主管
that you should be replaced
换成别人
as head of operations for the project.
为什么呢
Why is that?
你与外行星联盟的关系
Your ties to the OPA have been making a number of elders
让总会的一些长老们感到不安
in the general authorities uncomfortable,
尤其考虑到最近小行星带发生的事件
Particularly in light of the recent events in the belt.
外行星联盟旨在为全体小行星带人
The OPA is only interested in human rights
争取人权和工作
and jobs for all Belters.
还有在谷神星上挑起骚乱
And fomenting riots on Ceres.
还有利用坎特伯雷号事件煽动民众情绪
And inflaming passions in the wake of the Canterbury.
有组织宗教在历史上也不是没有过血腥暴力
The history of organized religion isn't exactly strife-free.
教会指示我向第谷公司要求一位新的项目主管
I've been asked to request a new head of operations.
当然 如果你们希望这样
Of course. If that's what you want.
但我有义务提醒你 没有我
But I'd be remiss if I didn't remind you that, without me,
你们可能很难找到技能最娴熟的小行星带人
you're going to have a very difficult time retaining
来建设你们的项目
the most skilled Belters for your project.
我是指那些真正认真负责的人
I mean the ones who build for reliability.
你们要派你们最优秀最聪明的摩门教徒
You're about to send your best and brightest Mormons
登上一场长达百年的旅程
on a hundred-year voyage
去往一个新太阳系的新行星
to a new world around a new sun.
谁知道路上有可能发生什么样的悲剧故障呢
Who knows what tragic malfunctions might occur along the way?
那么你打算找谁来替换我
So who'd you have in mind?
我们还在权衡考虑中
We're still weighing our options.
目前还请先一切照旧
For now, uh, please just continue along, as before.
太好了
Great.
我们要对诺伍号的传感器阵列
We have some calibration work to do
进行校准
on the Nauvoo's sensor arrays.
所以我要请你们的人先都下船
So I'm going to need you to get all your people off the ship
等我们完工了会通知你的
and I'll let you know when we're done.
可以行动了
We're good to go.
把所有的摩门教徒都赶下船
Get all the Mormons off the ship
将所有的传感器都对准唐纳吉尔号
and get those sensors pointed toward the Donnager.
我需要全面情报 快
I need a full report, now.
他们也有轨道炮
They've got rail guns, too.
我还从没见过这种大小的船上带轨道炮
I've never seen them on ships this size.
见鬼 我觉得他们在把能量转移到轨道炮
Shit. I think they're diverting power to the rail guns.
那就意味着我们进入近战状态了
That means we're in CQB.
-什么是近战 -域内近距离战斗
- What the hell is CQB? - A close quarter battle.
谁会疯狂到和唐纳吉尔号进行近战
Who would be insane enough to take on the Donnager in CQB?
该死 把我从这椅子上解开
God damn it, let me out of this chair!
我没必要在这里 让我回去和我的人在一起
I don't need to be here. Put me back with my people.
让他闭嘴或堵住他的嘴
Keep him quiet or gag him.
我需要知道这些船的身份
I want IDs.
我们得知道他们的作战能力
We need to know their capabilities.
抱歉 长官 火星舰队和联合国都找不到
I'm sorry, sir, but there's nothing matching their profile
和他们外形吻合的记录
in MCRN or UN records.
把各艘船的图像单独隔离出来
Isolate each vessel.
我要每艘船的
I want detailed imagery
详细图像和引擎特征数据
and drive signatures on every one of them.
舰长请到DC4区
Captain to DC-4.
我见过这样的船
I've seen a ship like that before.
第三艘和第四艘已摧毁
Splash three and four!
上尉 主引擎超载
Lieutenant, the main drive is overloading.
我们得把它关掉
We have to shut it down.
伙计们
Uh, guys...
-引擎关掉了 -好啊
- the drive's out. - Good.
不 这一点都不好
No, this ain't good at all.
作为一个凶狠的火星舰队小丑
You know, for a badass mickie navy boy,
你可真是个爱抱怨的小姑娘
you're a pretty whiny little bitch.
我只是个运输机驾驶员 你个野蛮人懂吗
I was just a transport pilot, you yahoo! You understand?
我从没受过这种情况的训练
I wasn't trained for this shit!
我只是个名字好听点的公车司机 满意了吧
I was a glorified bus driver, okay? You satisfied?
天啊 不应该发生这种事的
Oh, man, this is not supposed to be happening.
-亚历克斯 -不要 不要
- Shh, hey, Alex. - No, no, no, no, no, no!
看我这里有什么
Hey, hey, hey, hey! Look what I got.
一切都会好起来的 好吗
Everything's going to be okay, okay?
这会让你冷静下来
This is going to calm you right down.
相信我 我们不会有事...
Trust me, we're all going to be just...
我们得把洞堵住
We need to plug the holes!
一号轨道炮毁损 主警告灯开启
Rail gun one is down, master caution is lit.
有人受伤 医护人员到指挥中心
Man down! Medics to CIC.
你说你之前见过这艘船
You said you've seen this ship before.
有一艘和炸毁坎特伯雷号的船一模一样
One just like it blew up the Canterbury.
请安保人员检查船体
Can we get security to the hull, please.
他们停火了 为什么
They stopped firing. Why?
确认船体大面积受损
Confirm massive hull damage.
入侵舱在甲板着陆 我们被登舰了
Breaching pods on deck. We're being boarded.
舰长 这人有话和您说
Captain, this man has something to tell you.
现在不行 上尉
Not now, lieutenant.
你们正在对付的船
The ships you're fighting are
和炸毁坎特伯雷号的船一样
just like the ones that blew up the Canterbury.
不管是谁干的
Whoever's responsible for
他们想把这一切都怪到火星头上
this is trying to frame Mars for everything.
洛佩兹 把霍顿先生安全带离这艘船
Lopez, I want you to get Mr. Holden off of this ship
送回火星舰队指挥部
and safely back to MCRN command.
他是唯一能直接为这件事作证的人
He's the only person who can directly testify to this.
明白 长官 带他走
Understood, sir. Take him.
等等 没有我的船员我哪里都不会去
Hold on. I'm not going anywhere without my shipmates.
给他穿上太空服
Get him in his suit!
确保让这个和他一起离开
Make sure you get this off with him.
刚才空气从房间两边的洞里往外跑
The air rushed out of holes on both sides of the room,
这就意味着我们周围全是真空
Which means we're surrounded by a hard vacuum.
我们被困住了
We're trapped.
或许...或许我们可以强行打开这扇门
Maybe... maybe we can force the door.
-火星的密封门非常牢固 你知道的
- Mars builds too well, you know that.
就算打开我们也得完蛋 我们没有太空服
We'd still be screwed because we don't have our pressure suits.
大气循环系统还坏着
Atmosphere systems are still out.
我估计我们还剩大约20分钟的空气
I figure we have maybe 20 minutes of air left.
糟透了
Crap!
你在干什么
What're you doing?
镇静剂
Sedative.
这里面的量足够镇静我们中的一个
There's enough here to take one of us out,
延缓这个人的呼吸
which will slow down their breathing
减少我们的氧气消耗
and cut down our oxygen use.
-或许能多争取一点时间 -做什么的时间
- Maybe buy us a little more extra time. - For what?
你以为会有人来救我们吗
You think someone's going to come and get us?
我们没有通讯器 没法求救
We don't have comms, we can't call for help.
你有更好的计划吗
Do you got a better plan?
这是我的主意 我来
It's my idea. I'll take the shot.
不行 我们需要你保持清醒
No! We need you conscious.
他是地球人 他用的氧气最多 该让他来
He's an Earther, he uses the most air. He should do it!
我能背得动你 你背不动我
I can carry you. You can't carry me.
该死
Damn it.
我希望能醒过来
I wanna wake up.
我想谢谢你
I want to say thank you.
你明白的
You know,
为你一直以来对我的帮助
for helping me all those times you did.
你是个好人
You're a good person.
我本可以做个更好的人的
I could've been better.
我都没来得及说再见
I didn't even get to say goodbye.
对谁说
To who?
不重要了
It doesn't matter.
你知道最让我郁闷的是什么吗
You know what really chaps my ass?
我的船在受攻击 我的弟兄们在死去
The fact that I'm here protecting some lousy Earth taker
而我却在这里
while my ship's getting pounded
保护一个恶心的地球无赖
and my buddies are dying.
那你为什么不去帮他们 让我去帮我的人
Then why don't you go help them and let me go help mine.
我们有命令在身 在火星上职责是有意义的
We have our orders. Duty means something on Mars.
我倒很高兴让你走
I'd be happy to let you go.
我听说土卫九的事是你和你的朋友们干的
I heard you and your friends were responsible for Phoebe.
我对土卫九一无所知 你怎么不干脆问他
I know nothing about Phoebe. Why don't you just ask him?
后撤寻找掩护
Fall back and cover!
霍顿 后撤躲在我们身后 蹲下
Holden! Get back and stay back! And stay down!
霍顿 停下 见鬼 霍顿 回来
Holden, stop! God damn it, Holden! Get back here!
好了 我来了 什么事情重要到
Okay, I'm here. What's so important that I had to drop everything
让我放下手头的一切跑来这个破洞
and come to this hell hole?
认识这家伙吗
Recognize this guy?
认识 你在广场上找到的尸体
Yeah. The stiff you found in the square.
-我听说是起谋杀 -看看这个
- I heard it was a murder. - Look at this.
好棒 你查出他的身份了 工作就该这样
Great, you found his ID. That's how it's supposed to work.
这不是他 看到了吗
It's not him, see.
每次我扫描这家伙 都出来一个不同的身份
Every time I sample the guy, I get a different ID comes up
约翰
亨特
地球
12区42层
男性
相貌看起来都吻合
with a face that looks like it could be a match.
杰里米
吉斯派尔
火星
12区42层
男性
这尸体有很多体内植入物
Your stiff's got a lot of implants.
我猜他有个身份欺骗设备模块
I bet he has an ID spoofer mod.
专门设计来弄晕警察们
They're designed to spin cops,
让他们浪费时间追查错误的线索
waste their time chasing down false leads.
用这种东西的只有骗子们
The only guys who really use them are crooks.
成功的骗子们 这东西可不便宜
Successful ones. They're not cheap.
这些高科技的东西你一向比我强多了
You are way more of a gear-head than I ever was.
能帮我查出他的身份吗
Can you help me ID him?
米勒 你有一个搭档来帮你做这些事
Miller, you have a partner for this kind of stuff.
我试过给哈弗洛克打电话 他不希望被人找
No, I tried Havelock, he didn't want to be found.
我有时候也会这样
I've done the same from time to time.
求你了
Please?
好吧
Well,
如果他有欺骗设备
if he has a spoofer,
那他体内很可能还有一大堆违法的东西
then he's probably got a bunch of other shady shit in him.
标准内耳麦克
Standard inner-ear mike,
脊椎稳定器
spinal stabilizer,
胰腺泵
胰腺泵 普通型 给久坐的人用的
pancreatic pump, run of the mill, for the sedentary.
存储块
他腿里藏了一个存储块
He's got a memory crypt in his calf.
我们把它拿出来
Let's take it out.
-我去叫法医 -不要
- I'll get the coroner. - No.
那家伙话太多了
That guy talks too much.
来吧
Here we go.
寻找目标中
未抓取成功
见鬼
Damn it.
我又不会弄疼他
Well, it's not like I'm hurting the guy.
寻找目标中
抓取成功
找到了
There.
成功
Bingo.
内容被加密了 当然
Content's encrypted, obviously.
不过从文件名上看 应该是政府记录
But judging by the file names, these are government records.
好吧
Okay.
客户档案 公司研发...
Customs documents, corporate R&D...
这家伙是个数据倒卖贩
This guy was a data broker.
不管他倒卖了什么
Well, whatever he brokered,
一定足够重要到害他丧命的地步
must have been important enough to get him killed.
-你有什么事没告诉我 -没有
- What're you not telling me? - Nothing.
米勒
Miller.
你不知道比较好
It's better if you don't know.
我不需要你来保护我
I don't need you to protect me.
我没有保护你
I'm not protecting you.
我讨厌你这样做
I... I hate it when you do this.
谢谢了
Thanks.
哈弗洛克
Havelock.
接电话啊
Come on.
好吧 给他留言
All right. Leave him a message.
听着
Hey, look, um...
我不管你在干什么或者在干谁
I don't care if you're up to your whatever in whoever,
等你上来歇口气的时候
but when you come up for air,
我需要你帮我在沙迪那里打个掩护 好吗
I'm gonna need you to cover for me with Shaddid, okay?
我没法跟你说细节
I can't give you any details,
你自己想象一下吧 好吗
but just use your imagination, all right?
我知道只要你想 你很会做个卑鄙小人的
I know you can be a devious son of a bitch when you want to be.
我也会为你做同样的事的
I'd do the same for you.
天啊 天啊 我去叫人帮忙
Oh shit! Shit! I'll get help!
来人救命啊 有一位警官需要帮助
Somebody help! This officer needs help!
救命
Help me!
放手 别逼我杀你
Let go. Don't make me shoot you.
你不会的
You won't.
他的武器被盔甲锁定了 开不了枪的
His weapon is keyed to his armor, he couldn't have fired it.
不用客气
You're welcome.
莫尔死了 混蛋
Mole's dead, asshole.
对不起 真的很对不起 但除非你帮我
I'm sorry, I really am. But I won't testify to anything
把我的朋友也带离这艘船 否则我不会作证
unless you help me get my friends off this ship.
-闭嘴 我想对他问话 -遵命 长官
- Shut up. I want to speak to him. - Yes, sir.
他看起来可不像我见过的那些外行星联盟大兵
He doesn't look like any OPA grunt I've ever seen.
这技术比他们先进多了
Tech is way too advanced.
他是你的了
Yours.
你为谁工作 你们为什么要毁掉坎特伯雷号
Who are you working for? Why did you destroy the canterbury?
土卫九空间站 你在场吗
Phoebe Station. Were you there?
你在场 发生了什么事
You were. What happened?
认真听好了
Listen to me very carefully.
如果你想要医护人员来看你 就赶快交代
If you want medical attention, you start speaking now.
我们很快都会死了
We'll all be dead soon enough.
-走吧 -拜托了
- Let's go. - Please.
你得帮我去救我的朋友们
You have to help me get my friends.
你也不会把自己人抛下不管的
You wouldn't leave one of yours behind.
我们是火星军人
We're Marines.
我们发誓在必要的时候为他人牺牲
We've sworn to die for each other if we have to.
你都几乎不怎么了解他们
You barely know those other people.
他们在这里完全是因为我
They're only here because of me.
我和你作笔交易
I'll make you a deal.
谢德
Oh, Shed.
你没事吧
Hey, are you okay?
你回来了
You came back?
当然
Of course I did.
交易是这样的
The deal is this.
你们都要公开作证说火星
You will all testify that Mars had nothing to do
与坎特伯雷号的毁灭无关
with the Canterbury's destruction.
快穿好太空服 气封只是暂时性的
Suit up fast, the air seal is temporary.
我们得快走
We have to move.
-亚历克斯怎么了 -他替大家挨了一针
- What's wrong with Alex? - He took one for the team.
我来背他
I'll carry him.
来 伙计 穿上太空服
Come on, buddy. We gotta suit up.
我们不能再被阻拦了
We can't get pinned down again,
我们得找到一条安全通往停机坪的路
we need a clear route to the hangar bay.
我在努力 长官 但船上到处都是敌人
I'm trying, sir, but our ship is crawling with scumbags.
洛佩兹
Lopez.
听我说
Listen.
我们都失去了我们在乎的人
We've all lost people we care about.
而且我对整件事情一头雾水
And I don't even have a clue as to why.
但我不停地听到你们说起土卫九空间站
But I keep hearing about Phoebe Station.
如果我们都要因为它死去
And if we're all going to die because of it,
你能至少告诉我那里到底发生了什么事吗
can't you at least tell me what the hell happened there?
土卫九空间站失去联系好几周
Donnager was dispatched to Phoebe Station
唐纳吉尔号被派去查看
after she went silent for several weeks.
为什么
Why?
我们至今还是不知道
We still don't know.
上面所有人都死了 他们的尸体被烧成灰烬
Everyone on board was dead. Their bodies were incinerated.
我们找到他们被重新冻入冰道的墙里
We found them re-frozen to the walls of the ice tunnels.
我们以为是发生了火灾或者化学品泄露
We thought it was a fire or a chemical spill,
但随后我们发现所有的电脑核心都被摧毁了
but then we discovered that all the computer cores were destroyed.
你是说有人故意干的吗
You mean someone did it deliberately?
他们在掩盖什么事情
They were covering something up.
-什么事 -我不知道
- Like what? - I don't know.
老天
Jesus.
出什么事了
What happened?
舰长启动了零号程序
The Captain has set Condition Zero.
她要炸掉这艘船
She's going to scuttle the ship.
船体受损 四号甲板 情况紧急
Hull breach, deck four, critical.
登舰者正往工程仓 助动舱
Boarders are converging on engineering, aux,
零号程序显示
指挥中心和舰桥集结
CIC and the bridge.
准备好的备用舰离开停机坪了吗
Has the ready standby left the hangar bay?
没有 长官 还在那里
Negative, sir. It's still there.
-舰长 -还不到时候
- Captain. - Not yet.
这必须值些什么
This has to count for something.
杜基已就位
Dookie ready.
格兰姆斯已就位
Grimes in position.
把磁力靴关掉 尽快冲过去
Mag boots off. Move as fast as you can.
所有人听我口令 等待掩护火力
Everybody on my mark. Standby for cover fire.
你可不许在我面前倒下
Hey, hey! Don't you quit on me.
好了
All right.
准备好了吗
Ready?
跑
Go!
快跑
我们现在该怎么办
What the hell are we supposed to do now?
其他人呢
What about the others?
都死了 我们得赶紧离开
They're gone. We have to dust off now.
我不是飞行员 你得找别人来驾驶这艘船
I'm not a pilot. Someone else needs to fly.
-怎么了 -上去
- What? Whoa! - Go. Go!
将全船所有系统的操作控制权限
Authorize full operational
授权给现在船上的所有人
control of all systems for everyone now on board.
老大 我觉得我现在的状态...
Boss, I don't think I'm in any condition to...
-带我们离开 -没问题
- Get us out of here! - You got it.
我需要来些果汁
I need some juice.
好了 亲爱的 对我温柔点
Okay, sweetheart, be gentle with me.
人家可是第一次
This is my first time.
抱歉
Sorry.
设定机动规避路线 最大速度
Evasive maneuvers. Max burn.
别让任何人跟上我们
Do not let anyone stay on our tail.
没问题 老大 我是说 遵命 长官
You got it, Hoss... I mean... Yes, sir.
要是能在火星上看到大海就好了
It would've been nice to see an ocean on Mars.
-太刀号已经离开了 -长官
- The Tachi is away. - Sir.
舰长 这扇门快撑不住了
Captain, this door won't hold much longer.
我没想到我们会输
I didn't think we could lose.
我成功了 我成功了
I'm doing it. I'm doing it.
混蛋
Son of bitch.